Rommel B. Petilo

Lot 41 Block 4, St. Pio Street, Casa Blanca

Ampid I, San Mateo, Rizal, 1850 Contact No.: +639274665496 E-mail: rommel.petilo@gmail.com

Online Portfolio: ohmeng1984.github.io/webdevPort

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

A dedicated application developer with more than two years of experience in application design and database administration. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Experienced with PHP, MySQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, and VBA.

EXPERIENCE:

Sep 2019-Present

Shearwater Health Advisors Inc.

Software Engineer

- Meet regularly with business stakeholders and management to understand and refine business and functional requirements and determine project scopes and specifications
- Develop and maintain strategic operational systems, tools, and processes, including participation in tactical and strategic development projects
- Ensure software stability via regression, support quality assurance, and perform unit and useracceptance testing to identify bugs and ensure production operations run successfully
- Work quickly and carefully to complete small edits requested by customers, develop plans for completing larger projects, collaborate with colleagues, and suggest new solutions to improve existing websites
- Perform regular file backups to local directories for recovery

Mar 2012-Sep 2019

Reed Elsevier Phils.

Content Operations Editor

- Maintain, analyze, and enhance editorial content for online legal products of LexisNexis.
- Collaborate with vendor partners, engineering and other content operations/development teams and also troubleshoot, resolve problems and suggest process improvements.
- Reviewing and analyzing documents, designing, modifying and validating source content to ensure content integrity.

Feb 2008-Feb 2012 SPi Global

Data Technician/Content Editor

- Responsible for encoding of different information to the clients database.
- Carrying task that involves data/document analysis.

Mar 2007-Jan 2008

SPi Global

Data Management Staff

- Responsible for the delivery of processed files received from the client according to Company's productivity and accuracy standards and schedules. Responsible for checking the reliability of data or files to be delivered to the client.

June 2006-Nov 2006

Banco De Oro

Marketing Assistant

- Responsible for the redemption of freebies/giveaways and inventory check of supplies in the credit card division of Banco De Oro.

STRENGTHS:

- Programming Background:
 - ➤ VBA, HTML/CSS, Javascript/jQuery, AJAX, PHP, MySQL, Laravel, Version Control (Git), C#, C++, and XML.
- ➤ Technical aptitude for computer applications on systems (IT Networking, Microsoft applications, web-based applications and data analytics).
- Ability to work individually and as team member.
- > Strong learning agility. Able to learn quickly and apply knowledge.

EDUCATION:

COLLEGE:

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering 2001-2006 Central Colleges of the Philippines

SEMINARS/TRAININGS:

2021 "RPA Training (Automation)"

UiPath

July, 2020 "ANTstein Technical Training (Automation)"

Antworks

January-August, 2018 "Web Development"

Tuitt Coding Bootcamp

December, 2012 "Cisco 1-4 Modular Training"

Mapua IT Center